finally after five years of trading in
the markets I have perfected how to stay
out of drawdown in your challenge after
many challenges lost many challenges won
I have found the formula that works so
you stay out of drama
[Music]
all right what's up guys so in this
video we're going to be talking about
how to stay out of drawdown on your
regular account your challenge account
whatever the case is let's be honest
we've all been there and it sucks and
after five years I have finally
perfected the craft on how to do it
we're going to be talking about the
dopamine response we're going to be
talking about my 2.54 Rule and how to
recover when you're in drawdown in the
challenge so make sure you subscribe
let's get it
all right the dopamine response also
known as psychology let's be honest
trading is 90 psychology 10 technical
every Trader thinks they know that but
let me explain the reason why we get a
dopamine response is because our
training consists of is clicking buy or
sell at the right time and every single
time you take a trade you think it's the
right time to take your trade because
that's obviously the only reason why
you're taking it so you enter a trade
thinking you're going to make money so
you get this dopamine response this
feeling that yes I'm about to make all
this money but the majority of the time
you and losing the reason due to this is
because you're chasing that feeling
you're chasing that high that excitement
that you're going to make money online
by just clicking a couple buttons that
is not a case this is not a casino so
the solution to that is every single
trade you take to avoid the dopamine
response simply take it if it is a
logical business decision does this
trade make sense is it have a high
probability Trace setup is it a b or B B
plus setup and if it's not you don't
take it don't chase the high don't chase
the money chase a logical trading
decision
2.54 what is that so maybe a lot of you
guys have heard me say in the past 2.5 a
week is 10 a month a lot of these
funding companies the majority of them
they have a 10 profit Target so what I
did is I divided that into the 30 days
evaluation to give you which all you
have to do is divide 10 by four weeks
and that gives you 2.5 a week giving you
10 a month the funding company that I
use and I only trade on Rocket 21
challenge they have an eight percent
profit Target making it even easier to
pass so meaning you don't have to make
2.5 a week anymore all you have to do is
make two percent within the month and
this is a perfect point to talk about
now because we just came off of the
dopamine Phenom when you understand that
argument is two percent a week you're no
longer taking trades to get that high to
feel like you're involved in the markets
you're only taking logical trading
decisions to get your two percent within
the week so it's a very simple way to
take it takes away the dopamine feeding
takes away the full movie greed and you
just stick to your trading plan and your
roots two percent a week gives you eight
percent a month so you get Thunderbird
rocket then you're Training Center all
right so the third point is how to
recover your account from when it's in
drama let's be honest we've all had your
account and drawdown it's probably one
of the most difficult things to do so
the first thing in order to avoid being
a drawdown is you need to properly not
attack the dopamine feeling you don't
want to have that high of winning a
trade second you already know you need
to have a trading profit plan so which
is two percent a week is your your eight
percent a month and then the way to
recover your account the most ideal way
is to have a minimum of a one to three
risk reward and when you're in drawdown
in your account I highly highly highly
highly suggest that you don't come back
into the account wanting to pass it the
goal is to just bring it back to break
even once you bring the account back to
break even rocket21 they give you a
brand new challenge for free because if
you just manage to say a dollar but
let's say you have a hundred thousand
dollar account and you were down six
percent which is six thousand dollars
you have two trades that hit a one to
three risk reward only risking one
percent and you are just positive one
dollar and you've ran out of the 30
trading days they give you a brand new
account for free so the goal is when
you're in that in drawdown just recover
the account all the way to break even so
you get a new one and you start fresh no
need to go in and then try to pass it
because that way you just emotions are
everywhere and you're like trying to be
rushed you can't rush this process this
is a marathon not a Sprint and uh by the
way it's funny daily
[Music]
so I've been trying to get this daily
forever I bought this car like a month
ago when I finally got here so I got big
things coming for it yo subscribe
subscribe to the channel
I decided to do something completely
different nobody's done it and I'm gonna
be honest trading is super boring uh
probably 90 of my day is inside my house
doing nothing so I probably take one or
two trades a week and I just chill home
do nothing trading is extremely boring
it can get depressing by just being home
so I decided to do something different
and network meet other people what
better place than to come to L.A
I don't know everything
so where you guys coming from where are
you guys Long Beach are we around the
corner in like 30 minutes
San Diego Carlsbad yeah I mean
everything's got like 30 45 minutes from
like whatever yeah
except him he actually came for two
hours away two hours yeah that's San
Diego yeah
the challenges like to me at this point
it's easy yeah
um 2.5 a week five percent a month all
you need is one trade a week bro like if
your profit Target is 10 and all you're
looking is to get 10 percentage you get
2.5 a week gives you 10 a month and
that's it it's pretty much it it's my
goal this week just one trade
anymore personally my fomo is um
is uh I don't hold my trays long enough
bro
[Applause]
all right so we're gonna be giving away
three challenges a 25k 50k and 100K so
the way we're gonna do this is we got a
lot of people here I'm gonna pick a
number 1 through 100 and then whoever
gets the closest to it wins a 25k we're
gonna do it again for the 50k and then
when we get to the third challenge which
is the 100K we'll do a rock paper
scissors whatever wins it's 100K on me
right so I'm gonna pick a number 1
through 100 and I'm not gonna go to
every single one of you guys whoever
guesses it Guess The Challenge sounds
good 22 21 23 24 20 18 71.
44 13 19 58.
69 15 8 12 88. yo this guy
[Applause]
look look so you guys see look look we
screenshot it and everything look it's a
screenshot a screenshot hey Jose
number
you got one more yeah 24 38 22 44. 72 20
34 10 5 40 66 74 77.
about 45.
[Applause]
look no time last one all right last one
all right this is not trippy yo dude if
they get it again bro
I'll show you
guys can see it
55 89 82 50. 18. I'm 72 29 72 25 19 78
all right paper scissors
foreign
[Applause]
you tired
all right paper scissors
[Applause]
this first one is rock paper scissors
all right all right go run it all right
so so now it's about to be Rock Paper
Scissors Shoot
you guys ready
[Applause]
let's go like this make it even more
easier
by the crowded reaction we gonna know
who won
[Applause]
three two one Rock Paper Scissors Shoot
[Music]
California I drove all the way here just
for me my boy Alex Bro
I didn't do three times yesterday I said
bro let's kick it and then I say hey bro
I'm not weird we can FaceTime and
validate it and then I told him okay
let's go bowling bro
whoop it in front of my 100K account bro
I'm gonna buy this dude a 100K account
all right because it's only right bro
and I appreciate it
bro and I this was extremely funny bro
and like I needed a moment like this bro
I'm sorry like I needed a Moment Like
This just because I've been down so bad
bro and like this just feels so good and
this is my first time like pulling up to
like a professional Forex Trader but I'm
27 22. like I don't care about the age
age no matter Asian nothing but a number
if you're a girl
[Applause]